Heather Bjoin

GITHUB

https://github.com/Heatmarie

Minneapolis, MN 55403

LINKEDIN:

https://www

https://www.linkedin.com/in/heather-bjoin-bb833761

h.m.bjoin@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO:

309-371-0868

https://heatmarie.github.io/reactPortfolio/#info

"Never forget how much you enjoy coding." Those were words expressed to me from a client as I finished cutting his hair after a long talk about my experience in the Coding Bootcamp at the U of M. I have enjoyed the challenges given with each project and each new technology I have learned; I find them engaging and fulfilling, even more so when I have to struggle to get the final result. My ideal work environment is a place where I get to utilize my full stack skills with a team of developers who share my enthusiasm and have the desire to continue to learn.

Skills

- Node.js Express.js React.js MySQL MongoDB MaterialUI
 - JavaScript APIs JSON Responsive Design CSS HTML5

Projects

Poggers-POG (Plan on Gaming)

Two weeks

Poggers-POG is an app that allows users to sign into an account and add game titles and tasks to those goes. This was a full stack group project that utilized Handlebar templates, Express.js, Sequelize, MySQL, and Heroku.

Live Site: https://poggers-pog.herokuapp.com/
Repo: https://github.com/HeatMarie/poggers

EnviroPact

Two weeks

Enviro Pact utilized the MERN stack with MaterialUI, Chart.js and the ESG Enterprise which delivers ESG data to users. My tasks in this group project included helping design the layout and implement charts.

Live Site: https://enviropact.herokuapp.com/

Repo: https://github.com/HeatMarie/EnviroPact



Experience

GREAT CLIPS | WINDJAMMERS

Cosmetologist

Minneapolis MN

June 2019 - present

As a cosmetologist at Great Clips I ensure that each customer receives a quality experience and a quality haircut. It's all about great customer service, and being able to thoroughly communicate with every customer to ensure their satisfaction. In addition to helping customers, it's also essential to keep a clean salon. Together the staff works as a team, to make sure that our salon meets and exceeds the states requirements for cleanliness by following the sanitation guidelines.

GREAT CLIPS | PB5

Cosmetologist / Manager

Galesburg IL | Macomb IL

Aug. 2011 - Feb. 2017 | Oct. 2017 - June 2019

While working for PB5 (Great Clips) I was a hair stylist, and a manager. As manager, my tasks went beyond that of a stylist. I motivated my team to stay on task, made weekly schedules for the stylist, haircut training, and ensured customer satisfaction.

REGISTER-MAIL

Reporter (intern)

Galesburg IL

March - May 2019

As an intern at the Register-Mail I was able to get involved and write articles on several community events. Towards the end of my internship I had my own column that focused on good deeds that happened within the community.

Education

University of Minnesota Full-stack Web Development Certificate April - October 2021 Carl Sandburg College Associates of Arts May 2019